I seek refuge in Allah
from the outcast Shaitan .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
And to Allah belongs
the dominion of the heavens and the earth .
And to Allah is the destination .
I seek refuge in Allah from the outcast Shaitan .
In the name of Allah
so fight against the allies of Shaitan .
I seek forgiveness in Allah !
In the name of Shaitan ,
I swore !
You 'll suffer
from your guilt !
Alif .
Help me .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
As Su 'ala .
Enemy of Allah .
Praise be to Allah .
In the dawn , you 'll find sustenance .
In the dawn , you 'll find solutions .
- Ath ... - At-Talaq .
Verses 2 and 3 .
I know that .
Seek Allah 's forgiveness , Qodrat .
It 's been almost three years since Allah gave you His blessing .
To wake up each dawn .
I never asked to be woken up .
I also never asked to be released from this hell .
Qodrat !
I 've been here for decades .
You 're the only inmate to get a remission .
You 'll soon be a free man .
This blessing should make you remember
- ... that Allah ... - I have nothing left out there .
After Azizah .
Then Alif .
He took everything I had .
Help !
I already told you .
You 'll suffer for the rest of your life .
The only way
you can get out of this hell , Qodrat ,
is inside a body bag .
As Su 'ala !
Qodrat ! Help !
Help !
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
- Hold him . - Let go .
Quick !
Qodrat , wake up !
Allah is the greatest .
There is no god but Allah .
Muhammad is the Messenger of Allah .
Hasten to prayer .
Hasten to victory .
Allah is the greatest .
There 's no god except Allah .
Mama !
Let 's go !
THIS LAND BELONGS TO PESANTREN KAHURIPAN LOCALS ARE NOT ALLOWED
Come , hurry up .
Come on .
Thank you .
How 's Jihan ?
She 's getting worse .
She 's even paler .
She has a fever .
She doesn 't want to eat .
She wakes up in the middle of the night screaming in pain .
If not for you and the others ...
I wouldn 't know what to do .
Ti ...
Aside from coming to today 's prayers ,
I also need to see you .
Sorry , but I need you to pay back your debt to my late husband .
I haven 't paid my children 's tuition for three months now .
- The farm is not producing . No harvest . - Yas !
You 're not the only one .
Nobody 's farm in this village is producing any crops .
Jihan !
- Jihan ! - Jihan .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
Jihan .
Look at Mom ! Enough !
Enough , please ! Have mercy on your mother !
That 's enough , Jihan !
That 's enough , my child ! It 's Mom .
Please ... that 's enough , my love .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
Enough .
Jihan , enough !
Enough , Jihan !
Have mercy on your mother . Please .
Jihan ?
Jihan !
My god , Jihan !
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
One , two .
- I hit it , right ? - You 're okay , right ?
- You 're fine . - Come on , stand up .
I told you , you 'll be fine .
Peace be unto you .
Who are you ?
How dare you trespass here .
- Pardon my intrusion . I 'm ... - Qodrat !
Good Lord !
Jafar .
When did they let you out ?
I got a remission .
Thank goodness .
Jafar , why is the pesantren in this condition ?
Where 's Kyai Rochim ?
Since you left ...
At first , he was fine .
Even when he heard news about you ,
he 'd be smiling proudly .
Until ...
Until Alif 's death three years ago .
We 're all convinced , that was not an ordinary accident .
Every night he recited remembrances
and did night prayers just for you .
He neglected his own health .
Then , one day , for no reason ,
he fell ill .
The villagers started experiencing strange things .
The crops were infested .
Floods came . Diseases .
Even evil disturbances .
Were these attacks related to Kyai Rochim 's illness ?
I don 't know .
What happened , Qodrat ?
You and your unbelievable gift .
You , who never fails to exorcise people .
You saved countless lives because of it .
And this is what we got in return ?
What sin did you commit ,
that Alif became the victim ?
Ustadz .
I have to go .
You 'll sleep at the pesantren ?
Yes .
Forgive me , teacher .
Mom , I 'm full .
The food was delicious .
Why is your face like that ?
Nothing .
- I just miss you , Alif . - If you miss me , why are you sad ?
You should smile .
That 's better .
Why isn 't my sister Asha home yet , Mom ?
So , you 'll be playing with me , Mom ?
Go to bed after you 've finished dinner .
If you don 't want to , I 'm gonna play with Dad .
Dad .
Where is it , Dad ?
Alif .
Go to bed now .
What 's his name , Dad ?
Who is with you , Dad ?
Alif ?
What are you doing ?
I 'm playing with Dad .
If you miss Dad , that 's not how you play .
Peace be unto you .
And unto you peace .
Where have you been ?
I told you before , Mom .
I went to the plantation before going home .
You shouldn 't be out this late , Asha .
You know how the village is nowadays .
Stop exaggerating like the others , Mom .
Asha .
Jihan passed away this afternoon .
- I went there for the prayers ... - Mom .
I told you , Jihan was sick .
- She needed a doctor , not some spells ! - Seek Allah 's forgiveness , Asha !
Those are prayers , not spells .
What are spells ?
Have you eaten , Alif ?
Now go to sleep , Alif .
I still want to talk to Mom .
Having a talk or a fight ?
- A talk . - Sounds like a fight .
Come on , go to sleep .
The village is in a dire state .
Crops failed . Many got sick .
Now , Alif .
Did you know ?
He 's started talking to the wardrobe .
He said he was playing with Dad .
There are only the three of us now .
I only have you and Alif .
Why we should live like we 're in prison ?
Alif ...
We have to believe everything will be better .
Alif should have hope , not fear .
We need money .
That 's why I kept trying to earn money .
For your and Alif 's tuitions .
So you can go to college in town .
So we won 't have to sell Dad 's plantations .
What did you say ? Your life is like a prison ?
I 'm sure there are solutions for everything .
But we shouldn 't stay silent .
We shouldn 't lose to the fear that ...
Did you forget what happened because of your hope and courage for living ?
I know !
Our family is not complete because of Asha , right ?
Alif is paralyzed because of me , right ?
If any ...
- Alif ! - Alif !
Alif !
- Alif ! - Let 's move him .
- Alif ! - Alif !
Alif !
He 's got a fever , Sha .
- Alif ! - I 'll get a cold towel .
- Make hot sweet tea too . - All right .
Alif , wake up , son .
Son . It 's Mom . Wake up . Alif !
Alif , do you hear me ? Open your eyes .
Alif !
Alif .
Yesterday , I went to the plantation because I missed Dad .
Look , Alif .
I drew this .
Dad used to tell me stories .
This was the yard for you to play in .
Alif still has a fever ?
Yes , Mom . He still has a fever .
Go to school , you 'll be late .
Sha , I 'm ...
Me too , Mom .
Me too .
- Peace be unto you . - And unto you peace .
Where 's my wardrobe ?
I moved it into storage .
We will buy a new one later .
Alif , I made this for you .
Have a bite . Come on , eat .
Why did you do that ?
If you don 't want it , just say so .
I 'll cook your favorite dish .
Get some rest .
Glory be to Allah and all praise be to Allah .
There is none worthy of worship except Allah .
Glory be to Allah ...
Where 's Alif ?
- What is it , Mom ? - Where 's Alif ?
I don 't know . He 's not with me .
Alif !
- Alif ! - Alif !
- Alif ! - I mean it .
I 'm not lying .
Alif ?
I want to go with you .
Really ?
We can just play together .
I want to go with you .
What are you doing here , Alif ?
We 've been looking everywhere for you .
Dad said
that I don 't need the others .
Alif , that 's enough .
As long as I obey him ,
Dad said I can walk again .
Dad is gone . He 's dead !
Don 't talk trash about Dad !
Alif !
Alif , it 's me ! It 's Mom , son !
Dad is dead !
Shut up , you bitch !
I seek forgiveness in Allah !
- Alif ! - Mom !
Why did you lock him up , Mom ? Alif !
Watch the door ! Don 't let him out .
- Why are you leaving him ? - Wait till I get back !
Alif !
Peace be unto you !
Peace be unto you ! Help !
- And unto you peace . - Help .
Just a moment .
- I need to see Ustadz Jafar now ! - Be calm , ma 'am . Seek Allah 's forgiveness .
- How did you get wounded ? - Where 's Ustadz Jafar ?
He 's out , I don 't know where .
Are you an Ustadz ?
My son is possessed . Please exorcise him .
I beg you ! Help him .
Sorry , Ma 'am . You can come back when Ustadz Jafar returns .
- Excuse me . - I can pay you !
As I said before ,
you can come back when Ustadz Jafar is back .
- Please leave . - Please , Ustadz , I can 't .
- I 'll give him your message . - I can 't lose my son !
Please help him , Ustadz !
Please , help my son .
Open up . Open the door , sis .
What did I do wrong ?
Why are you mean like Mom ?
- Mom locked you up , not me . - Liar !
You 're the one who wants to lock me up .
You and Mom always left me alone at home .
No . I love you , Alif .
If you love me ,
why don 't you celebrate your birthday with the family ?
Dad and I went looking for you .
I love you , Alif .
If you love me ,
why did you make me paralyzed ?
why did you cause the accident that night ?
Dad was right .
You and Mom don 't love me anymore .
Dad 's gone , Alif !
Dad is here .
You still don 't believe me ?
Come see for yourself .
Alif ?
Come here , sis .
Come here . You said you loved me .
Alif , come on out .
Let 's go home .
I don 't want to .
I want to play with Dad .
Listen to me , Alif .
Come out now !
All right .
But give me back my feet !
Let 's put it here .
Looks nice in here .
Looks nice .
We 're busted , Mom .
- Happy birthday , Asha . - Happy birthday , sweetie .
Happy birthday , Asha .
Dad and Alif were going to pick you up .
But it seems my gorgeous daughter has come home .
What 's wrong , Asha ?
Tell Daddy all about it .
Don 't cry .
May Asha be smarter , more mature ,
and a great and famous painter .
And love Alif even more .
And I hope we can always be together .
So , I can always celebrate your birthday .
Always , Dad .
But now .
Let 's cut the cake .
So all of our prayers and hopes
can come true .
What 's wrong , Asha ?
I don 't know . Suddenly , my hand hurts .
If everything is all right ...
then come on , cut the cake .
Come on . Try again .
- But it hurts . - It 's okay . Just do it slowly .
Mom ?
Let me help .
Don 't stop .
- But it hurts , Dad ! - Again .
- Mom . - Again !
You don 't want me to leave again , right ?
Don 't want to lose me again , right ?
Then ,
cut the cake .
Cut !
Asha ?
Mom ?
Asha !
Mom !
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
Asha ...
It hurts , Dad .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
There is neither might nor power but with Allah .
Asha .
Mom .
Endure it , Asha . Endure it .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
- Oh , Lord . - Alif .
Who are you ?
Alif .
Tell me your name !
You 're a hypocrite , Son of Adam !
You call on Allah 's name ,
but you have no faith in Him .
You kneel to Allah ,
but you question His power .
Alif !
I seek refuge in Allah from the outcast Shaitan .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
Those who believe do battle for the cause of Allah
and those who disbelieve do battle for the cause of idols .
So , fight the minions of the devil ...
You 're beneath me !
Remember , hypocrites belong in hell .
... the devil 's strategy is ever weak .
Once again , tell me your name .
Khadaab !
What 's your faith ?
Dajjalul Mustafan .
I only worship Shaitan .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
Alif !
Glory be to Allah and all praise be to Allah .
There is none worthy of worship except Allah , and Allah is the Greatest !
You 'll convert to Islam .
With Allah 's permission , leave this child 's body .
I seek refuge in Allah from the outcast Shaitan .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
O company of jinn and men .
If ye have the power to penetrate all regions of the heavens and the earth ,
then penetrate them ! Ye will never penetrate them save with our sanction .
Which is it , of the favors of your Lord , that ye deny ?
Just you wait !
Soon , those who are stronger will come
to destroy Muhammad 's people .
There is neither might nor power but with Allah .
Alif ?
Alif !
Thank you , Allah .
My job is done .
Thank you .
Ustadz .
Qodrat .
My name is Qodrat .
As Su 'ala .
Help me , Dad .
What 's wrong , Mom ?
Asha !
Dear Lord .
Find Ustadz Qodrat . Quick !
Mom !
Mom ? It 's Alif .
Mom ?
Good evening .
We 've come for Alif .
Wait !
Jafar ?
Where 's Alif ?
Alif !
- Alif ! - Qodrat !
- What are you doing ? - I must save Alif . There 's no time .
Qodrat ! Let 's talk .
- There 's no time . I must save Alif . - Alif ?
- I must save him . - He 's my responsibility now .
You don 't know who you 're dealing with .
He 's a sorcerer . A direct descendant of Shaitan .
As Su 'ala .
Jafar !
Look at Alif , Jafar !
Look !
He is feasting on our faith !
Our lives are just his playthings .
The jinn I eradicated from Alif 's body was only one of his henchmen .
So , please .
Let me exorcise Alif .
Qodrat , every day I exorcise the villagers in this village ,
so I know more about ...
But that 's the infidel jinn that murdered my son !
He also tried to kill me in the prison .
And now he 's here in the village .
Please .
That 's why I don 't need your help .
Look at that kid .
He 's Alif Amri .
Not Alif Al-Fathanah .
And for now , he 's still breathing .
Don 't make the same mistake twice .
Look deep within your heart .
Are you helping in the name of Allah ,
or for your revenge ?
I testify there is no god except Allah .
I testify Muhammad is Allah 's messenger .
Peace be unto you .
Why us , Ustadz ?
Why Alif ?
Seek Allah 's forgiveness , Sha .
That 's what Shaitan wants .
For us to doubt Allah .
Allah is the greatest .
And Islam is the perfect religion .
But you and me ...
We 're weak .
Every day , we breathe to reach heaven , but we forget .
We don 't realize we 're full of sins .
Is there a place for me in heaven ?
I have caused harm to the two people I love the most .
Did you do it on purpose ?
Allah knows everything we have done .
And everything we did will have consequences .
But not in our human minds .
We don 't have the right to question .
Allah won 't burden humans beyond their limits .
Allah does not burden a soul beyond its capacity .
Each will enjoy what good he earns .
You can recite the Qur 'an ?
Praise be to Allah .
- What are you doing here ? - Peace unto you , sir .
- Peace unto you . - You 're from Pesantren Kahuripan ?
Yes , that 's correct .
So , you 're one of Jafar 's men .
Tell him !
My daughter is dead !
So , there 's no one to exorcise anymore .
Wait , sir . I don 't understand .
If Jihan were alive
and you still took our land and plantations ,
we 'd still die anyway from starving because there 's nothing left .
- Do you know that ? - Wait , sir . What land ?
The whole village knows !
You 're using religion for your greed !
For wealth and money ! Go away ! Go away from here !
The village has become a dreadful place because of your people !
- Ustadz ! - Enough , sir .
Go away !
Tanti !
- Mom ! - Sha , that 's Alif .
- Alif ! - Praise be to Allah .
- Thank you . - Your son has been healed .
Thank goodness .
Alif 's exorcism went well .
He can go home now .
- What did you get from Yasmin 's family ? - Let 's go .
Money ?
Or a piece of their land ?
Who told you that nonsense ?
- That 's slander . - That 's blackmail .
- They were gifts from the villagers . - You robbed them !
- They gave it themselves . - If they don 't give it , you won 't help .
Just like Tanti 's daughter .
It was only a matter of time for Jihan .
- Many villagers need my help . - So , who do you help first ?
Those who can pay ? Am I right ?
The land and plantations that I asked from them
are for the new pesantren
and a new mosque .
You said it yourself , why is this pesantren a mess ?
I want to make this pesantren alive again .
All of it is useless ...
if the people around here are living in misery because of you .
Which is more important ?
A new pesantren
or the greater good ?
Don 't touch Yasmin 's land and plantations .
And never again ask for payment for exorcism .
It 's our duty , Jafar .
Don 't disgrace Kyai Rochim .
Kobar .
Go pack Ustadz Qodrat 's things .
He 's too holy to stay here .
Yes , Ustadz .
What kind of horse gets tired the most ?
Sis ?
- I 'm sorry , Alif . - No .
- Alif , will you forgive me ? - No .
- Forgive me . You 'll forgive me , right ? - Yes , stop it .
- Forgive me . - Stop it !
Why aren 't you asleep ?
- Mom , look at what Asha did . - Why me ?
Alif .
Ustadz Jafar said a prayer over this water for you to drink .
A spell , right ?
A prayer , not a spell .
So , what is a spell ?
Say , " In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate , " before drinking .
Oh , you 're right . " In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate . "
Sha . I need to talk to you about payment ...
Mom .
- I 'm gonna check it out . - I 'm coming with you .
Stay here with Asha .
- Mom ! - I 'm here . Calm down .
Where 's Mom ?
What 's taking her so long ?
- Alif , what horse ... - No .
- Wait here , Alif . - Sis !
Sister !
- Sis ! - Just a moment , Alif .
Mom ?
Sis ?
Is that Mom ?
- Mom ? - Sis !
Be patient , Alif .
Mom ?
- Mom ? - Asha ?
Is that Mom , sis ?
Mom ?
Asha .
Mom ? Why ...
Go to the pesantren now and find Ustadz Jafar .
- Now , Mom ? - Now , Asha .
All right . Peace be upon you .
Asha . Sister !
Sis ?
Where are you , sis ?
Please forgive me , Kyai .
I have to go .
I 'm ashamed that I can 't do anything for this pesantren .
Qodrat ...
Glory be to Allah .
Kyai ?
Jafar ...
Idols .
It 's late . Kyai Rochim need his rest .
- You should go now . - Kyai .
- Wake up , Kyai . - Hey !
- Where 's Jafar ? - Ustadz Jafar is busy , so please leave .
Hey !
Go home while you still can .
Thank you .
Jafar !
I 'll summon this spell for jinn and ghost .
I worship Shaitan with all my heart .
Give all your power to me .
I made these sacrifices to please you .
So , please receive it .
Give me the power to rule the world .
For all Shaitan
jinn and ghost .
I give it all to you .
The soul of Alif Amri .
Take it all to complete the ritual .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
Welcome , Qodrat .
Jafar , you infidels !
Hypocrite ! All of this time , you said Allah 's name , but ...
Since when have you heard me reciting Allah 's verses ?
I forget when the last time was that I said His name .
All this time you lived off this pesantren and Kyai Rochim .
This is how you repay him ?
Lived ? Rats are alive too .
Drink this blood .
Follow me .
We 'll worship As Su 'ala .
You filth !
One more time .
Follow me .
Worship As Su 'ala .
Or I 'll force you to worship As Su 'ala .
We worship You , Allah , alone ,
and no one else .
And only in Allah do I seek protection .
Then it 's your fate to die by my hand today !
Ustadz !
What are you doing to me , Mom ?
I can 't move .
Why can 't I move , Mom ?
Enough , Mom .
Help .
Mom ?
- Mom ? - Asha !
Where 's Alif , Mom ?
Where 's Alif ?
A prophecy told me
there 'd be one of Muhammad 's people
who stood in the way of my misleading human souls .
Where 's Alif ?
Every time , I failed to kill you .
Failed to overthrow your faith .
But not today .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
Peace be unto you , Ustadz Qodrat .
Mom !
In the name of Allah and Prophet Muhammad , where 's Alif ?
Which Alif ?
The one whose neck I broke ?
Or the Alif I just buried alive ?
Alif !
As Su 'ala . Allah have mercy .
I seek refuge in Allah from the outcast Shaitan .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
Your god is one god ; there is no god save Him .
... the Beneficent , the Merciful .
In the creation of the heavens and the earth .
And the difference of night and day .
And the ships which run upon the sea with that which is of use to men , and ...
Repent .
I seek forgiveness in Allah .
And the water which Allah sendeth down from the sky ,
thereby reviving the earth after its death ,
and dispersing all kinds of beasts therein ,
and in the ordinance of the winds
and the clouds obedient between heaven and earth ,
are signs of Allah 's sovereignty
for people who have sense .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
Ustadz !
I 'll kill all religious men .
So , no one will pray .
And the sound of adhan will vanish .
Allah is the best place for us to surrender .
Our best protector and the best helper .
Glory be to Allah and all praise be to Allah .
There is none worthy of worship except Allah .
And Allah is the Greatest .
Glory be to Allah and all praise be to Allah .
There is none worthy of worship except Allah .
And Allah is the Greatest .
I won 't let you mock Allah 's verse .
I seek refuge in Allah from the outcast Shaitan .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
Say O Muhammad : It is revealed unto me that a company of the Jinn gave ear .
And they said : Lo ! We have heard a marvelous Qur 'an
Allah is the greatest .
I testify that there 's no god except Allah .
which guideth unto righteousness
so we believe in it and we ascribe no partner unto our Lord .
Mom !
Asha .
Where 's Alif ?
Where 's Alif , Sha ?
- Alif ! - Mom !
Dig him up ! Alif !
Dig , Sha . Get him out ! Help me !
- Help him , Asha ! - Mom !
Save him ! Alif !
Alif !
My son ! Wait for me !
Wait for me !
Asha ! Help Alif !
Quick !
You came , Dad .
I knew you 'd come to find me .
What 's wrong , Dad ?
I 'm scared . It 's dark down there .
Ustadz ?
I 'm alone there .
Please come with me , Dad .
I don 't want to lose you again .
And we 'll find Mom there .
And we 'll be together again .
Please help me , Dad .
Help me .
Come on , Asha .
I love you , Alif .
I 'll always miss you .
I seek refuge in Allah from the outcast Shaitan .
In the name of Allah , the merciful and compassionate .
All praise to be to Allah .
Lord of all the Words . King of the Day of Judgment .
You alone we worship , and to you alone turn for help .
- Guide us , O Lord , to the straight path . - But we all belong to Allah .
The path of those You blessed .
- Not of those who ... - And to Allah we shall return .
Indeed , to Allah we belong and to Allah we shall return .
Blasted human !
If I can 't destroy you ,
I 'll make you lose everything !
He said : Now , because Thou hast sent me astray ,
verily I shall lurk in ambush for them on Thy Right Path .
I seek refuge in Allah from the outcast Shaitan .
And I came to them ...
- ... from the front , behind them ... - In the name of Allah ...
- ... left and right . - Allah ! There is no god but He .
- And you 'll find most of them ungrateful . - The Living , The Self-subsisting , Eternal .
His are all things in the heavens and on earth .
Who is there can intercede in His presence except as He permitted ?
He knoweth what appeareth to His creatures as
before or after or behind them
nor shall they encompass aught of His knowledge except as He willeth .
His throne doth extend over the heavens and on earth .
And on earth , and He feeleth no fatigue in guarding and preserving them
for He is the most high . The Supreme in glory .
With Allah 's permission , come out from this child 's body !
Let Allah punish you in the afterlife !
I testify that there 's no god except Allah .
And I testify that Prophet Muhammad is Allah 's messenger .
Allah is the greatest .
There is neither might nor power but with Allah .
- Alif ! - Alif !
Alif !
Indeed , to Allah we belong , and to Allah we shall return .
- Walk slowly , Kyai . - Let 's go .
Allah willing , I 'll stay healthy .
Can 't you stay a little longer ?
Six months flies .
- Peace be unto you , Kyai . - And peace unto you .
And peace unto you .
- Take care , Kyai Rochim . - All right .
Almost every day we fixed up this pesantren .
I lost track of time .
It 's time for me to go .
The time has come for me to find out what happened to Azizah .
This journey is a mandate for bearing the gift that Allah gave to you .
But never forget this place , and don 't hesitate to come back .
Because this is your home .
Allah willing .
And
for a while , before this old geezer ...
Let my old bike keep you company on your journey .
Good Lord !
- Thank you , Kyai . - You 're welcome .
- I 'll be going now . - Take care .
There 's no one comparable to Him .
Ustadz Qodrat !
Mom ?
Ustadz Qodrat will be back , right ?